Preliminary Guide to the Edwin Burmeister Papers, 1960-2011 RL.00178
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Edwin Burmeister papers
1960-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Burmeister, Edwin
RL.00178
14.4 Linear Feet
Professor of Economics at Duke University. Collection contains teaching materials, research files, writings, correspondence with other economists, papers and presentations, and personal files chiefly related to Burmeister's work as a professor of economics at Duke University, the University of Virginia, and the University of Pennsylvania. Many collection materials document Burmeister's research on Capital Theory, Economic Growth Theory, and Arbitrage Pricing Theory (APT).
10,800 Items
Access Restrictions
Some materials in the collection are restricted due to FERPA law and University Archives policy. See box list for details.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Edwin Burmeister Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in June 2008.
Biographical Note
Professor Edwin Burmeister joined the Duke faculty as a Research Professor in 1991. He previously taught at the University of Virginia and the University of Pennsylvania. After receiving his undergraduate and M.A. degrees from Cornell, Burmeister completed his graduate studies at M.I.T., where he earned his Ph.D. in 1965. He has published numerous articles in the areas of mathematical economics and economic theory, particularly in the fields of capital theory, economic growth, and macroeconomics. He was elected a Fellow of the Econometric Society and served as editor of the International Economic Review and associate editor of several other journals.
Collection Overview
Collection contains teaching materials; research files; writings; correspondence with other economists, including Paul Samuelson; papers and presentations; and personal files chiefly related to Burmeister's work as a professor of economics at Duke University, the University of Virginia, and the University of Pennsylvania. Many collection materials document Burmeister's research on Capital Theory, Economic Growth Theory, and Arbitrage Pricing Theory (APT).
Economists -- United States; Capital -- Mathematical models; Economics -- Study and teaching; Economics; Economic development -- Mathematical models; Duke University. Department of Economics; University of Pennsylvania. Dept. of Economics; Burmeister, Edwin; Burmeister, Edwin; University of Virginia; Samuelson, Paul A. (Paul Anthony), 1915-2009
- Accession 2008-0122, 1960s-2008; Accession 2016-0126, 1970-2011, 24 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  Portions of these accessions are closed under FERPA and University Archives policy.
  - Arbitrage Pricing Theory (APT) research, writings, notes (Box 1-2)
  - Teaching materials (Box 1-2)
  - Lecture notes (Box 1-2)
  - Referee reports (Box 3-4)
  - Correspondence (Box 3-4)
  - Research files (Box 3-4)
  - Teaching materials (exams and syllabi) (Box 3-4)
  - Research files (Box 5)
  - Teaching materials (Box 5)
  - Paul Samuelson materials (Box 6)
  - Writings (Box 6)
  - Teaching materials (Box 7)
    Separated Materials note
    [Disk 001 removed and contents transferred to server]
  - Lectures and conference presentations (Box 8)
  - Writings (Box 8)
  - Lectures and conference presentations (Box 9)
  - Capital Theory and Dynamics: Publisher correspondence (Box 10)
  - Lectures and talks (Box 10)
  - Research files (Box 11)
  - Materials on inflation (Box 11)
  - Teaching materials (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (Box 12)
  - Writings (Box 12)
  - Teaching materials (Box 13)
  - Recommendations (RESTRICTED) (Box 13)
    This box requires curator review for restricted content prior to circulation.
  - Career files (RESTRICTED) (Box 13)
  - Capital Theory and Dynamics notes (Box 14)
  - Notes and drafts for work with Ken Wall, 1978-1982 (Box 14)
  - Teaching materials (Box 14)
  - Bound volumes: Ingersoll lecture notes (Box 15)
  - Unpublished works (Box 15)
  - Recommendations and reviews (RESTRICTED) (Box 15)
  - Writings (mostly reprints on Arbitrage Pricing Theory (APT) with McElroy) (Box 15)
  - Reprints and typescripts of articles (Box 16)
  - Research notes (Box 16)
  - Equal Organic Composition Capitol (EOCC), 2006 (Box 16)
  - Career and personal files (RESTRICTED) (Box 17)
  - Career files, curriculum vitae (Box 18)
  - Presentations and papers for conference in Rome, 1995 (Box 18)
  - Research and consulting files (Box 19)
  - Research files and notes (Box 20)
  - BIRR reports and related materials (Box 20)
  - Paul Samuelson correspondence (Box 20, Box 25)
    Scope and Contents
    Box 25 includes one file of correspondence between Burmeister and Samuelson dated 1975.
  - Teaching materials (Box 20)
  - Masters Thesis, 1962 (Box 21)
  - Typescript copy of an unpublished work by Bishop (Box 21)
  - Aggregate Production Function Project materials (Box 22)
  - Notes and tests from classes taught by Solow and Modigliani (Box 23)
  - Teaching notes (Box 23)
  - Independent study papers by Burmeister's students (Box 24)
  - Typescript copy of Capital Theory and Dynamics (Box 24)
  - A. Rodney Dobell materials, 1970, 2011, and undated (Box 25)